Guide to the Adele Gutman Nathan Theatrical Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1834-1985; Series I; 5.25; (13 boxes)
  - PAGEANTS
    - Weirton Steel Company
      - 1942 Labor Day Celebration
        - "Attack" [play]
          - Radio version, typescript, photocopy, 1942 Sep 7 (Box 10, Folder 295)
          - Radio version, typescript, photocopy, corrected, 1942 Sep 7 (Box 10, Folder 296)
        - Cast lists, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 297)
        - Clippings, 1942 Sep (Box 10, Folder 298)
        - Photographs
          See: Oversize, Box 27, folder 854
        - Programs, 1942 Sep (Box 10, Folder 299)
        - Weirton Steel Employees Bulletin
      - 1943 Labor Day Celebration
        - Clippings, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 300)
        - Photographs, 1943
        - Program, 1943 Sep (Box 10, Folder 301)
        - "We Hold These Truths" [play], typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 302)
        - Weirton Steel Employees Bulletin
      - 1944 Labor Day Celebration
        See also: Pageants, War Bond campaign, Box 10, folder 291
        - Clippings, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 303-4)
        - Programs (Box 10, Folder 305)
        - Weirton Steel Employees Bulletin
        - The Weirton Worker, 1944 Sep 7 (Box 10, Folder 306)
    - Wings of a Century
      - Budget memo, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 307)
      - Creditor notice, 1937 Mar 17
      - Program, 1934
    - Youth United
      - Advertisement, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 308)
      - Radio interview script pages, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d.
      - Setting plans, 1943 Dec (Box 10, Folder 309)
      - Script, printed, 1944
    - Unidentified pageants
      - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 310)
  - RADIO SCRIPTS
    - Beyond the Call of Duty
      - Circular postcards, [1942?] (Box 10, Folder 311)
    - Catholic Charities Fund Appeal
      - Correspondence, 1943 Jun (Box 10, Folder 312)
      - Interview program, typescript, carbon, 1943 Jun 10 (Box 10, Folder 313)
      - Note, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 314)
      - Programs schedule, 1943
      - Variety program, typescript, carbon, 1943 Mar 27 (Box 10, Folder 315)
    - [ Comrade Borozova ]
      - Typescript pages, photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 316)
    - Flashbacks by Paddy
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 317)
      - Draft pages, typescript, carbon and holograph, corrected
    - How Things Started
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 318)
    - It's A Man's World
      - Typescript, carbon, 1941 May 29 (Box 10, Folder 319)
    - New Frontiers
      - Outline page, [1938?] (Box 10, Folder 320)
    - One Hundred Years with Youth
      - Typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 321)
    - Opinion Requested
      - List of panel members, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 322)
      - List of questions, 1945 Jun 10
      - List of radio stations, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 323)
      - Publicity material, 1948
    - Report from the Front
      - Typescript, carbon, 1944 Jan 22 (Box 11, Folder 324)
    - The Story of All of Us
      - Advertising pamphlets, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 325)
      - Typescript, photocopy, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 326)
    - Thats News
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 327)
    - They Chose to Die
      - Background material, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 328)
      - Outline, n.d.
      - Typescript pages, carbon, n.d.
    - Today's News For Tomorrow's Citizen
      - Typescript, carbon, 1944, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 329-31)
    - Your Rights and Mine
      - Typescript, photocopy, corrected, 1940-41 (Box 11, Folder 332-33)
    - We've Got Something
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 334)
      - Series list, n.d.
  - SHORTER WORKS
    "Bargain Rates," letter to the New York Times Book Review
    - Letter, 1982 Oct 27
    - Printed column, 1982 Nov 21
    - "Batya"
      See also: "Forty Days of God". Box 11, folder 349
      - Research correspondence, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 336)
      - Draft, typescript, carbon, with cover letter, 1978 Aug 13 (Box 11, Folder 337)
    - "Blinky" drafts, typescript, carbon, 1964 Dec (Box 11, Folder 338)
    - "Cactus Concerto"
      - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 339)
      - Drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected
      - Notes, 1948-50 (Box 11, Folder 340)
      - Photographs, 1948
    - ["Cellar Theatre"], typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 341)
    - The Children's Monthly Review, printed pages, 1901 (Box 11, Folder 342)
    - [Christmas Poem], holograph, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 343)
    - "The Cone Collection of Baltimore," Vogue magazine, printed pages, 1950 Mar 1 (Box 11, Folder 344)
    - "The Day Lincoln Spoke," The Supplement [?], photocopy, 1963 Nov 21 (Box 11, Folder 345)
    - "Du Vin Ordinaire," typescript with cover letter, 1928 May 29 (Box 11, Folder 346)
    - ["Eating in France"], typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 347)
    - "Forbidden Sweets," drafts, typescript, 1979, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 348)
    - "Forty Days of God," typescript, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 349)
      See also: "Batya." Box 11, folder 336
    - "Freedom in the Midst of Servitude," Jewish Comment, printed page, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 350)
    - "French Ladies Don't Do It," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 351)
    - "Gigolo on Horseback," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 352)
    - "A Good Contact with the Coast," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 353)
    - "Grandfather Stories - Politics," typescript, corrected, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 354)
    - "A Home For Cinderella: Bringing Settlement Drama Out of the Scullery," The Survey
      See: Personal Papers, Scrapbook 1, Pages 14-15, Box 22, folder 726
    - "Horse Geriatrics"
      - Typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 11, Folder 355)
      - Photographs, n.d.
    - "I Always Talk to Strangers," drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 356)
    - "I Was a Confirmed Insomniac," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 357)
    - "Jungle Plot"
      - Draft 1, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 358)
      - Draft 2, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 359)
      - Draft 3, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 360)
      - Draft 4, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 361)
      - Draft 5, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 362)
    - ["Kiddie Corner"], typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 363)
    - "A Kitchen in Florence," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 364)
    - Letter to The New York Times, draft page, typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 365)
    - "Lincoln's Unknown Gettysburg Address," Civil War Roundtable of New York Newsletter, printed pages, [1978?] (Box 11, Folder 366)
    - "Little Theatres are Big Business," typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 367)
    - "Little Theater That Grew," photocopy, 1947 Apr 27 (Box 11, Folder 368)
    - ["Mathematics"], draft pages, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 369)
    - "Mencken and the Little Theatre Movement"
      - Theatre Arts, photocopy, corrected, 1951 Jun (Box 11, Folder 370)
      - Clippings, 1962, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 371)
      - Notes, 1962
      - Publisher's correspondence, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 372)
      - Drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 373)
      - Menckeniana, nos. 3 and 4, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 374)
    - "A Mencken Memento," Menckeniana, nos. 43 and 44, with note, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 375)
    - "A Mild Retort," typescript, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 376)
    - "Mr. Mencken Hoists His Own Petard," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 377)
    - "My Grandfather Sticks to His Principles," typescript, annotated (Box 12, Folder 378)
    - "My Grandmother Has Some Houseguests" draft pages, typescript, 1980 Jun 13 (Box 12, Folder 379)
    - "My Grandmother's Funeral," typescript corrected (Box 12, Folder 380)
    - ["Nancy Sommers"], notes, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 381)
    - "Notorious at Ninety," draft pages, typescript, corrected, 1984, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 382)
    - "100% American," typescript, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 383)
    - "One Price Silk and Lace House," typescript, corrected (Box 12, Folder 384)
    - "The Other End of the Microscope," draft pages, typescript, corrected (Box 12, Folder 385)
    - "The Other Gettysburg Speech," drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 386)
    - "Pageant Production" draft pages, typescript, corrected (Box 12, Folder 387)
    - "Pageantry," Americana Encyclopedia, printed pages, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 388)
    - ["Play Directing"], draft pages, typescript, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 389)
    - "A Play Coordinator," typescript, carbon, with letter, 1935 Aug 22 (Box 12, Folder 390)
    - Producing Tercentenary Pageants
      See: Pageants, American Jewish Tercentenary, background material, program planning booklets, Box 8, folder 226
    - ["Renee and Paul"], typescript (Box 12, Folder 391)
    - "Russ Smith Variety Show Speech," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 392)
    - ["A Salon in Paris"], typescript, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 393)
    - ["Salzburg, Vienna and Dresden"], typescript (Box 12, Folder 394)
    - "Sleepers Awake," drafts, typescript, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 395)
    - "Solid Success," The Freeman, 1953 Jun 1 (Box 12, Folder 396)
    - Song lyrics
      See: Oversize, Box 27, folder 855
    - "Speech for Mrs. Herbert Lehman," typescript, carbon, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 397)
    - "Springboards to Success," drafts, typescript, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 398)
    - "Sterling Calder" [Speech given at Baltimore Museum of Art]
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 399)
      - Draft, typescript, 1975 Dec 14
      - Press release, n.d.
    - "The Story of Radio Mike," drafts, typescript, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 400)
    - "Street Scene: 1928," New York Times Magazine, printed pages, 1947 Feb 2 (Box 12, Folder 401)
    - "Success Story," typescript, photocopy, 1947 May (Box 12, Folder 402)
    - "Tempora Mutantor," typescript, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 403)
    - "Ten Pillars of Poise," typescript, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 404)
    - "Two Musical Events," typescript, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 405)
    - "The Vagabonds Come to Town," drafts, typescript, carbon, 1946, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 406)
    - "Vag. Theatre," drafts, typescript, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 407)
    - "The Voice of the Ticker," This Week, printed page and note (Box 12, Folder 408)
    - "The White Steps of Baltimore"
      - Outlines, 1963, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 409)
      - Drafts, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1958-78
    - "William Thompson's Scalp," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 410)
    - Miscellaneous pages and notes (Box 12, Folder 411)
  - STAGE PLAYS
    - [ Dr. Crawford Long ], draft pages, holograph, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 412)
    - Knights of Song
      See also: Motion Pictures, Melody Makers, Box 8, folder 209
      - Clippings, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 413)
      - Correspondence, 1960 Apr 6 (Box 12, Folder 414)
      - Draft page, typescript, carbon with letter, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 415)
    - A Midsummer Night's Dream
      - Correspondence, 1923 Aug 1 (Box 12, Folder 416)
      - Note, n.d.
      - Storyboard, 193? (Box 12, Folder 417)
      - Scripts
        - Version 1, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 418)
        - Version 2, typescript, photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 419)
        - Version 3, typescript, photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 420)
      - Musical accompaniment by Mendelssohn, 1929 Jan (Box 12, Folder 421)
      - Program and Invitation, Brooklyn Academy of Music, [1930?] (Box 12, Folder 422)
      - Program, Cove Theatre, 1931 Aug 24 (Box 12, Folder 423)
      - Program, Emanuel Sisterhood Play School, 1926 Aug (Box 12, Folder 424)
    - [ The Persians ], script pages, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 425)
    - Soup, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 426)
    - What's Wrong with American Music?, typescript, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 427)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Brieux, "The School for Mothers-in-Law," The Smart Set, printed pages, 1913 Sep (Box 13, Folder 428)
    - Cone, Edward J. "The Miss Etta Cones, the Steins and M'sieu Matisse," American Scholar, with reprint pamphlet, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 429)
    - Conrad, Joseph, One Day More, The Smart Set, printed pages, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 430)
    - Davis, Blevins, [Untitled poem], typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 431)
    - Evreinov, Nicholas, A Merry Death, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 432)
    - Fetherstonhaugh, V., Harrison, The Smart Set, printed pages, 1914 Jul (Box 13, Folder 433)
    - Horner, Harry, Rehearsal Time: A Sketchbook, [signed], 194? (Box 13, Folder 434)
    - Hurst, Fannie
      - "Here Comes Mrs. Roosevelt," typescript, photocopy, 1968 Jan 30 (Box 13, Folder 435)
      - "This I Believe...," printed page, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 436)
    - Katchmakoff, Atanas
      See: Shorter Works, "Batya," Box 11, folders 336-37 and "Forty Days of God," Box 11, folder 349
    - O'Neill, Eugene, Bound East For Cardiff, typescript, carbon, annotated, 191? (Box 13, Folder 437)
    - Patton, Gerri
      - Rare, outline, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 438)
      - [Untitled memoir], typescript photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 439)
- Projects, 1919-84; Series II; 0.75; (2 boxes)
  Series II, Projects, is arranged alphabetically by the name of the project in which Adele Gutman Nathan was involved. Several types of projects (e.g. stage plays, pageants, associations) are represented here.
  - American Heritage Foundation
    - Pageant guidelines, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 440)
  - Baltimore Museum of Art
    - Correspondence, 1973-76, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 441)
  - Baltimore Music Club
    - Correspondence, 1947-76 (Box 14, Folder 442)
    - History, 1948
    - Press release, 1925 Dec 5 (Box 14, Folder 443)
    - Programs, 1923
  - Camp Wah-Na-Gi
    - Brochure, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 444)
    - Photographs, n.d.
  - Cellar Players
    - Clippings, 1924-34, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 445)
    - Playbills, 1925-41, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 446)
    - Scrapbook 1, 1925, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 447)
    - Scrapbook 2, 1922-30 (Box 14, Folder 448)
  - Children's Playground Association
    - Report, 1919 (Box 14, Folder 449)
  - Columbia University Bicentennial Celebration
    - Broadsides, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 450)
    - Invitation, 1954 Jul 16 (Box 14, Folder 451)
    - Photographs, [1954] (Box 14, Folder 452)
    - Program, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 453)
  - East Carolina Teachers College
    - Senior Class Play Program, 1922 Apr 21 (Box 14, Folder 454)
  - Federation for the Support of Jewish Philanthropic Societies
    - Annual Dinner program, 1930 Oct 19 (Box 14, Folder 455)
  - Get Out and Vote Campaign
    - Proof sheet, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 456)
  - The Grachur Club
    - Bound East For Cardiff, program, 1921 Dec 16 (Box 14, Folder 457)
  - Lenox Hill Players
    - Programs, 1929, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 458)
  - Lincoln Group of New York
    - Membership List, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 459)
  - Lions International Convention
    - "Carolina Jamboree," program, with notes, 1956 Jun 28 (Box 14, Folder 460)
  - Little Lyric Theatre
    - Circular letters, 1921, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 461)
    - Clippings, 1921-50
    - Programs, 1920-24 (Box 14, Folder 462)
    - Reports, 1921-22
  - National Association of Manufacturers
    - Congress of American Industry program
    - 67th Congress of American Industry, program, 1962 Dec (Box 14, Folder 463)
    - Public Relations Advisory Council Group, "Let George Have It!" program, 1942 Dec 1 (Box 14, Folder 464)
  - Newswomen's Club of New York
    - Biographical sketch, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 465)
    - Front Page Award
      - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 466)
      - Program, 1981 Nov 20
  - New York World's Fair. Illinois Commission
    - "Great Moments with Mr. Lincoln," speech transcript, 1964-65 (Box 14, Folder 467)
    - Overseas Press Club of America
      - Bulletin, 1984 Dec (Box 14, Folder 468)
      - Dateline '84, 1984
      - Delinquent dues list, 1968 Jan 30 (Box 14, Folder 469)
      - Personal statements, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 470)
      - Photographs, 1954-66
      - Who's Who clippings, 1945, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 471)
  - Reds [motion picture]
    - Advertisements, 1981-83 (Box 14, Folder 472)
    - Clippings
      - Gossip columns, 1979, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 473)
      - Nathan, Adele Gutman, 1979, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 474)
      - Pre-release publicity, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 475)
      - Reed, John, 1981-82 (Box 14, Folder 476)
      - Reviews, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 477)
    - Correspondence, 1979-80 (Box 14, Folder 478)
    - Interview questions, [1979] (Box 14, Folder 479)
    - Movie program, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 480)
  - Shanghai Tiffin Club
    - Newsletter, 1973 Jan 18 (Box 15, Folder 481)
  - Syrian Junior League
    - Blue and Green Mat [play]
      - Clipping, 1930 Jan 23 (Box 15, Folder 482)
      - Program, 1930
  - Theatre for Children
    - Planning notes, 1938, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 483)
  - Town Club Players
    - Clipping, 1929 Mar 22 (Box 15, Folder 484)
  - Vagabond Players
    - Clippings, 1916-81 (Box 15, Folder 485)
    - Correspondence, 1953, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 486)
    - Play notice, The Drama magazine, 1925 Dec (Box 15, Folder 487)
    - Production notes, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 488)
    - Programs, 1925-76
  - The Wandering Generation [motion picture]
    - Advertisements, 198? (Box 15, Folder 489)
  - The Woman Pays Club
    - Biographical sketches, 1972-73, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 490)
    - Directories, 1973, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 491)
    - Invitations, 1975-83 (Box 15, Folder 492)
    - Personal statements, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 493)
    - Photographs, n.d.
    - Press release, 1979 May (Box 15, Folder 494)
  - Works Progress Administration Federal Theatre
    - Clipping, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 495)
    - Programs, [1937?], n.d. (Box 15, Folder 496)
- Correspondence, 1862-1989; Series III; 1; (2 boxes)
  Series III, Correspondence, is arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - "A" general, 1936-86 (Box 16, Folder 497)
  - Allvine, Glendon, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 498)
  - [Ames, Winthrop?], n.d. (Box 16, Folder 499)
  - "B" general, 1939-83 (Box 16, Folder 500)
  - Baltimore & Ohio Railroad Company, 1951-57 (Box 16, Folder 501)
  - Budd, Ralph, 1953, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 502)
  - "C" general, 1954-85, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 503)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank, 1943-86 (Box 16, Folder 504)
  - Coburn, Charles, 1918, 1927, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 505)
  - Colum, Padraic, 1916, 1925 (Box 16, Folder 506)
  - Cone, Edward
    See: Writings, Books, Victorian in Bohemia, research material, correspondence, Box 4, folder 106
  - "D" general, 1923-72 (Box 16, Folder 507)
  - Davis, Blevins, 1955-62 (Box 16, Folder 508-09)
  - Diamant, Anita, 1981, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 510)
  - Dorsey, Rhoda
    See: Goucher College, Box 16, folder 515
  - "E" general, 1930 (Box 16, Folder 511)
  - "F" general, 1975, 1984, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 512)
  - Fogel, Edward A., 1971 (Box 16, Folder 513)
  - "G" general, 1957, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 514)
  - Goucher College, 1976-86 (Box 16, Folder 515)
  - Goucher College Club of New York, 1962, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 516)
  - Goucher College Library, 1957, 1984, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 517)
  - Gutman, Ida, 1886-1924, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 518)
  - Gutman, Louis K., 1885-1907
  - "H" general, 1932-74, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 519)
  - Hochstadter, Adolph, 1862, 1899 (Box 16, Folder 520)
  - Hungerford, Edward, 1948, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 521)
  - Hurst, Fannie, 1942-65, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 522)
  - Ioli, Georgiana, 1986 Apr 3 (Box 16, Folder 523)
  - "J" general, 1957, 1978, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 524)
  - Joseph, Nannine, 1954-61, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 525)
  - "K" general, 1945-84 (Box 16, Folder 526)
  - Kaye, Elizabeth Gutman, 1934-62, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 527)
  - Keaton, Diane, 1982 Jan 27 (Box 16, Folder 528)
  - Kern, Jerome, 1924 Dec 26 (Box 16, Folder 529)
  - Kissel, Howard, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 530)
  - Knights of Malta, 1967 May 20 (Box 16, Folder 531)
  - Kroll, Leon, 1923-24, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 532)
  - "L" general, 1938-83 (Box 16, Folder 533)
  - Levy, Eleanor, 1980-86, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 534)
  - The London Shop, 1971-80 (Box 16, Folder 535)
  - Lyons, Sylvia, 1985-86 (Box 17, Folder 536)
  - "M" general, 1925-84 (Box 17, Folder 537)
  - MacPherson, Aimée Semple, 1938 (Box 17, Folder 538)
  - May, A. Wilfrid
    See: Writings, Victorian in Bohemia, correspondence, Box 4, folder 106
  - Mencken, August, 1951 Aug 8 (Box 17, Folder 539)
  - Mencken, H. L., 1916, n.d.
  - Messer, Thomas
    See: Writings, Victorian in Bohemia, research material, Box 4, folder 106
  - "N" general, 1954-81 (Box 17, Folder 540)
  - Newberger, Betty, 1886 (Box 17, Folder 541)
  - New York Times, 1955, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 542)
  - "O" general, 1977-78, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 543)
  - O'Neill, Eugene, 1917-20, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 544)
  - "P" general, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 545)
  - Patterson, Marjorie, 1917-18, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 546)
  - Patton, Gerri, 1969-83, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 547)
  - "R" general, 1926, 1958, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 548)
  - Real magazine, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 549)
  - Rothschild, Bessie, 1968-78 (Box 17, Folder 550)
  - "S" general, 1916-82 (Box 17, Folder 551)
  - Scharf, Peg, 1979, 1985, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 552)
  - Sotheby-Parke Bernet Galleries, 1972-75 (Box 17, Folder 553)
  - "T" general, 1968-85 (Box 17, Folder 554)
  - Thorne, Alice, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 555)
  - University of Maryland, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 556)
  - "V" general, 1925, 1928 (Box 17, Folder 557)
  - "W" general, 1927-82 (Box 17, Folder 558)
  - White, Fred, 1983, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 559)
  - Yale University, 1982-83 (Box 17, Folder 560)
  - Zambulan, Uccia, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 561)
  - Unidentified letters
    - from "Art", n.d. (Box 17, Folder 562)
    - Regarding genealogy, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 563)
    - Miscellaneous, 1925-86 (Box 17, Folder 564)
  - Unidentified greeting cards, 1985, 1989, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 565)
  - Invitations, 1952-86, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 566)
  - Advertisements, 1939-86 (Box 17, Folder 567)
  - Blank postcards, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 568)
  - Empty envelopes, 1938-82 (Box 17, Folder 569)
- Personal Papers, 1886-1987; Series IV; 3; (5 boxes)
  Series IV, Personal Papers, is arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Appointment books, 1942-82 (Box 18, Folder 570-74)
  - Auction announcement, 1941 Feb 10 (Box 18, Folder 575)
  - Awards
    Army-Navy "E" Decoration
    Civil War Roundtable of New York Barondess Award
    - Weirton Steel Employees Bulletin
    - See: Oversize, Box 28, folder 856
    - Announcement, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 576)
    - Clippings, 1963
    - Newsletter, 1981 Feb 12 (Box 18, Folder 577)
    - Photographs, 1963
    - Goucher College Alumna Award
      - Correspondence, 1980-81 (Box 18, Folder 578)
      - Guidelines for Nomination, annotated, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 579)
      - Response to Guidelines for Nomination, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 580)
      - List of activities, 1972, 1977, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 581)
      - Biographical sketch, drafts, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 582)
      - Personal statement, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 583)
      - Speech notes, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 584)
      - Press release, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 585)
      - Press release mailing list, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 586)
      - Schedule of events, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 587)
      - Program, 1981 Oct (Box 18, Folder 588)
      - Photographs, 1981 Oct (Box 18, Folder 589)
      - Biography notice, Class Notes, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 590)
    - Valley Forge Freedoms Foundation
      - Nomination form, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 591)
      - Photographs, [1957?] (Box 18, Folder 592)
  - Biographical information
    - BBC Interview audiocassette, 1982 Mar 25 (Box 18, Folder 593)
    - Clippings, 1921-75, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 594)
    - Interview, La Prensa, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 595)
    - Miscellaneous biographical sketches, [1976?], n.d. (Box 18, Folder 596)
    - Notorious at 90 [documentary]